[The Shinsengumi are sharing ghost stories to cool off at night. Inayama-san's story is "Woman in a Red Kimono."]
[A cursed voice is heard at midnight. What did Hijikata see?!]
(稲山)あれは 今日みたいに
蚊が たくさん飛んでる➡
It was a very hot night with many mosquitoes, like tonight...
暑い夜だったねぇ…｡
I was setting off fireworks with my friends and noticed it had gotten dark.
ｵﾚ 友達と一緒に花火やってたら➡
いつのまに 辺りは
真っ暗になっちゃって｡
(稲山)いけね 母ちゃんに
ぶっ飛ばされるってんで➡
So, I thought my mom would get upset and kick me if I didn't get home right away.
帰ることになったわけ｡
I decided to go home.
We cleaned up the exploded fireworks and glanced at the Temple School.
それでね 散らかった花火
片づけて➡
ふっと 寺子屋のほう 見たの｡
(稲山)そしたらさぁ
もう真夜中だよ➡
Then, although it was midnight,
そんな時間にさぁ
寺子屋の窓から➡
a woman in a red kimono was looking right at me from the window of the Temple School.
赤い着物の女が こっち見てんの｡
ｵﾚ もう ぎょっとしちゃって
でも気になったんで➡
I was shocked, but I wanted to find out more.
恐る恐る 聞いてみたの｡
So I gingerly asked her what she was doing up this late.
｢なにやってるの？ こんな時間に｣
って…｡
(稲山)そしたら その女
ﾆﾔｯと笑ってさ…｡
And she...
...smiled at me and said...
(土方)ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞが
足りないんだけど！
We've run out of mayonnaise!!
(悲鳴)
Vice-chief!! What the heck-?! You ruined the ending!!
(隊士)副長！
なんてことするんですか➡
大切なｵﾁを！
知るかぁ！
I don't care about that! The mayonnaise ran out! I told you to buy more.
ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞが切れたんだよ｡
買っとけって言っただろ！
(土方)焼きそばが
台なしだろうが！
Yakisoba's no good without it!!
(隊士)もう十分
かかってるじゃねえか！
You've had enough, already!
なんだよ それ
もはや 焼きそばじゃねえよ！
That doesn't look like Yakisoba anymore! It's "Yaki-mayonnaise" now!
黄色いﾔﾂだよ！
(隊士)あれ 局長？
Oh, Chief!
うわっ！
Chief!!
(隊士)局長～！
My goodness! Chief!
(隊士)大変だ！
局長が ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞで気絶したぞ！
The mayonnaise made him faint!
最悪だぁ～！
It's terrible!
くだらねえ… どいつもこいつも➡
That's so stupid! They're all obsessed with ghost stories.
怪談なんぞに ﾊﾏりやがって…｡
There's no way that ghosts exist.
幽霊なんぞ
いてたまるかってんだよ｡
(蚊の羽音)
Man, there're so many mosquitoes these days.
なんだ？
最近 やたら 蚊が多いな…｡
≪死ね… 死ね…｡
Die...
Die...Die...Hijikata...
≪死ねよ 土方…｡
≪お前 頼むから
死んでくれよ…｡
Please, die...
It can't be...
まっ まさか ﾎﾝﾄに…｡
What are you doing here at this time of night?
なにしてんだ？
ﾃﾒｴ こんな時間に…｡
(沖田)ｼﾞｮ… ｼﾞｮｷﾞﾝｸﾞ｡
Jo...Jogging.
You liar!
ｳｿつくんじゃねえ！
そんな格好で走ったら➡
If you ran around in that kind of outfit, your head would catch fire!
頭 火ﾀﾞﾙﾏになるわ！
Were you holding a ritual? You were holding a ritual for killing me, weren't you?!
儀式だろ？ ｵﾚを抹殺する
儀式を開いていただろう！
(沖田)はぁ…
ﾎﾝﾄに自意識過剰な人だ｡
You're really self-consciousness.
(沖田)そんなんじゃ
ﾉｲﾛｰｾﾞになりますぜ｡
If you think like that, you'll suffer a nervous breakdown.
なにをっ！
What?!
どうしたんでぃ？ 土方さん｡
What's the matter with you, Hijikata-san?
総悟… 今 あそこに
何か見えなかったか？
Sogo, did you just see something over there?
(沖田)いいえ 何も…｡
Nothing really...
確かに 今…｡
I thought I just saw...
(隊士)ぎゃぁ～！
["Watch Out for Conveyor Belts!"]
(土方)ひでえな まったく…｡
That's terrible...
Hey, how many people so far?
(土方)おい これで 何人目だ？
Eighteen troops.
(沖田)えぇっと… 18人目でさぁ｡
(沖田)隊士の半分以上が
やられちまったわけですね｡
So over half the squad has been struck down.
さすがに ここまでくると
薄気味悪いや…｡
I've got to admit... This is getting kind of eerie.
冗談じゃねえぞ｡
天下の真選組が➡
No kidding. We, the Shinsengumi, were brought to our knees by a ghost,
幽霊にやられて みんな
寝込んじまっただなんて➡
Everyone flat on their backs. It's mortifying! I can't even tell anyone about it.
恥ずかしくて どこにも
口外できんよ｡ 情けねえ｡
The shame!
(近藤)ﾄｼ… ｵﾚは違うぞ！
Toshi...
I wasn't beaten by a ghost.
I was beaten by mayonnaise!
ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞにやられた！
よけい 言えるか｡
That's even worse.
Everybody is making delirious sounds about the woman in the red kimono.
みんな うわごとのように➡
赤い着物を着た女と
言ってるんですが➡
稲山さんが話してた
怪談の あれかな…？
Is that the same ghost Inayama-san was talking about the other night?
ﾊﾞｶ野郎！
幽霊なんざ いてたまるか｡
Idiot! There's no such thing as ghosts.
霊を甘くみてたら
とんでもないことになるぞ ﾄｼ｡
Don't underestimate ghosts, or you'll be in real trouble, Toshi.
この屋敷は 呪われてるんだ｡
This building is cursed. It must be possessed by a horrible spirit.
きっと とんでもない霊に
取り憑かれているんだよ｡
なにを ﾊﾞｶな…｡
What are you talking about?!
No, never.
いや… ないない｡
(山崎)局長！ 連れてきました｡
Chief, here they are.
おう！ 山崎 ご苦労！
Oh, thanks, Yamazaki!
I found these exorcists downtown.
街で捜してきました 拝み屋です｡
(銀時)どうも｡
Hello.
なんだぁ？ ｺｲﾂらは｡
Who are these guys? Is the circus in town?
ｻｰｶｽでもやるのか？
いや
霊を祓ってもらおうと思ってな｡
No, they're here for a exorcising.
おいおい 冗談だろ｡
こんなうさんくさい連中…｡
Hey, hey! Are you kidding?
These guys look so shady.
Oh? Your back...
(神楽)おぉ…
あら おにいさん 背中に…｡
なんだよ？ 背中になんだよ？
What...? There's something on my back?
ﾍﾍﾍ ありゃ もうﾀﾞﾒだな…｡
He's done for with that on him.
なにｺｲﾂら！ 斬っていい？
斬っていい？
What are they doing? Can I stab these jokers? Huh, can I?
先生… なんとかなりませんかね？
Sensei, can you help us? I'm too scared to go to the bathroom by myself.
このままじゃ 怖くて
１人で厠にも行けんのですよ｡
任せるね ｺﾞﾘﾗ｡
We'll take care of it, gorilla.
あれ 今 ｺﾞﾘﾗって言った？
ｺﾞﾘﾗって言ったよね？
Huh? Did you just say "gorilla"? You just said gorilla, right?
ざっと 屋敷を
見させてもらいましたがね➡
We looked around the house.
こりゃ 相当 強力な
霊の波動を感じますな ｺﾞﾘﾗ｡
And I feel a fairly powerful spirit presence, gorilla.
(近藤)あっ 今 確実に
ｺﾞﾘﾗって言ったよね？
Ah, you definitely said "gorilla," didn't you?
(神楽)まぁ… とりあえず
除霊してみますかね｡
For starters, why don't we do an exorcism?
こりゃ 料金も
相当 高くなるｺﾞﾘよ｡
This is going to cost you a pretty penny, gorilla.
(土方)おいおい なんか
口癖みたいになってるぞ｡
Hey, hey, they're getting in the habit of saying "gorilla."
して 霊は いかようなものｺﾞﾘか？
うつったぁ！
By the way, what kind of spirit is here, gorilla?
It's contagious!
え～っと… 工場長｡
Um... A factory foreman.
えぇっと… ﾍﾞﾙﾄｺﾝﾍﾞｱに
はさまって死んだ➡
Well, it's the spirit of a factory foreman who died after getting stuck in a conveyer belt.
工場長の霊です｡
But everyone said they saw a woman's spirit.
あの… みんなが見たって
言ってるのは➡
女の霊なんですが…｡
(新八)間違えました｡
Oh right!
ﾍﾞﾙﾄｺﾝﾍﾞｱにはさまって死んだ
工場長に似てるって言われて➡
It's the spirit of a woman who looked like the factory foreman who killed herself
by getting stuck in a conveyer belt.
自殺した女の霊です｡
That explanation's too long! And what does a factory foreman have to do with it?!
(土方)なげえよ！
工場長のくだり いるかぁ？
とりあえず お前…
山崎とかいったか｡
Anyway, are you Yamazaki?
(山崎)えっ？
お前の体に➡
We must borrow your body. To draw in the spirit, and then exorcise it, okay?
霊をおろして除霊するから｡
(山崎)えっ… ちょ ちょっと
待ってください｡
Eh... W-Wait a minute.
あの… 除霊って
どうやるんですか？
Wait... "Exorcise"... How are you gonna do that?
お前ごと しばく！
We'll just hit you really hard.
Hey, anybody can do that!
なんだぁ？ それ
誰でもできるじゃねえか！
(神楽)はっ！
ﾊｰｲ！ 今 これ 入りました｡
霊 入りましたよ これ！
Yes! It went into him. A spirit went into him, here!
霊っていうか… ﾎﾞﾃﾞｨｰﾌﾞﾛｰが➡
Looked to me like you delivered a body blow instead of putting a spirit in.
入ったように見えたんですけど…｡
No, I went into him.
違うよ 私 入りました｡
え～ 皆さん 今日で
この工場は つぶれますが➡
Well, this factory will be destroyed today, and it's all my fault...
責任は すべて私…｡
Hey! It's the factory foreman!
(近藤)おいぃい！
工場長じゃねえか！
あれ？ なんだっけ｡
Oh? What was the story again?
ﾊﾞｶ お前！ ﾍﾞﾙﾄｺﾝﾍﾞｱにはさまれて
死んだ女だよ｡
Idiot! It's about a woman who died after getting stuck in a conveyer belt.
ﾍﾞﾙﾄｺﾝﾍﾞｱにはさまれる女なんて
いるわけないでしょ｡
There's no way a woman would get stuck in a conveyer belt.
A conveyer belt... Oh? What type?
ﾍﾞﾙﾄｺﾝﾍﾞｱに… あれ？
もういいから 普通の女 やれや｡
Never mind! Just act like a normal woman!
ﾑﾘよ！
普通に生きるっていうのが➡
No way!
Playing a normal woman may look easy, but it's the most difficult acting there is!
簡単そうで いちばん難しいの！
誰も そんなﾘｱﾘﾃｨｰ
求めてねえんだよ！
Nobody expects that level of realism!
(神楽)うるさい！ ﾐｲﾗ男｡
Shut up, mummy man! Your outfit is what's unrealistic!
(神楽)お前の格好に
ﾘｱﾘﾃｨｰがなさすぎね！
なんだと ｺﾗｧ！
こんなんしてたほうが➡
Say that again?! I thought I look mysterious like this.
ﾐｽﾃﾘｱｽだろうが！
Oh, no! Cut it out, you guys!
あぁ もう お前らやめろや！
仕事中ですよ！
ちょっと 聞いてんの ２人とも！
We're on duty! Hey, are you listening to me?
Both of you!
Ah.
We didn't mean any harm. We didn't have a job.
悪気は なかったんです｡
仕事も なかったんです…｡
夏だから お化け退治なんて
儲かるんじゃねえの？ って➡
We just thought exorcising ghosts might be a good job
to make money because it's summer and it's blazing hot in town.
街 触れ回ってたら…
ねぇ 銀さん！
Right, Gin-san?
そうだよ！ ｵﾚ 昔から
霊とか見えるからさ｡
Right. I've been able to see spirits for a long time,
それを 人の役に立てたくて…｡
so I wanted to use my special talent to help people.
あっ ｷﾐの後ろに➡
Oh, I see an angry old granny behind you.
めちゃめちゃ怒ってる
ばばあが見えるね｡
ﾏｼﾞですかい？
きっと駄菓子屋のばばあだ｡
Really? She must be the granny who owned the candy store.
ｱｲｽの当たりｸｼﾞ 何回も偽装して➡
I made fake winning tickets to get ice cream lots of times.
だましたから 怒ってんだ…
どうしよう｡
I cheated her, so she must still be mad at me. What should I do?
心配いらねえよ｡
Don't worry. She said if you release all of us and give us water, she'll forgive you.
ｵﾚたちを解放して 水を与えれば
全部 水に流すってよ｡
(沖田)そうか｡ わかりやした｡
All right. Then drink this up through your nose.
(沖田)じゃあ これ
鼻から飲んでくだせえ｡
んっ？ ｲﾀﾀﾀﾀ…！
Ow-ow-ow-ow-ow-ow-ow!
What's this nostalgic feeling?!
なに これ!?
なんだか 懐かしい感覚！
昔 ﾌﾟｰﾙで溺れたときの感覚！
Like when I was a kid and almost drowned in the swimming pool!
あうっ あうっ…！
Gin-chan, I feel like my head is going to explode... Help me!
銀ちゃん 私 頭 爆発しそう｡
ﾊﾞ～ﾝって…｡
助けて…｡
お～い！
Hey! An innocent girl says her head is going to explode!
いたいけな少女が
頭 爆発するってよ～！
いいのか ﾃﾒｴら！
このｱﾆﾒ 終わるぞ ｺﾗ～!!
Are you guys sure you want the show to finish like this?!
次回から ｢真選組 血風帳｣ｽﾀｰﾄ！
Next week, We'll start "Shinsengumi: Wind of Blood Chronicles"! Don't miss it!
みんな 絶対 見てくれよな！
あ… これ ﾎﾞｸら殺されますね｡
They're going to kill us.
誰か助けて～！
Somebody, help me!
おい ﾄｼ！
そろそろ降ろしてやれよ｡
Hey, Toshi, cut them down. Otherwise, Sogo will discover the joys of sadism.
いいかげんにしないと
総悟が Ｓに目覚めるぞ｡
What are you talking about? He's a prince from a sadistic planet. It's too late.
な～に言ってんだ｡ ｱｲﾂは
ｻﾃﾞｨｽﾃｨｯｸ星から来た王子だぞ｡
もう 手遅れだ…｡
あ～ 気持悪いよ…｡
うえ～｡
I don't feel so good.
Normally we'd beat you and cut you in strips...
本来なら ﾃﾒｴら
たたき斬ってやるとこだが➡
あいにく ﾃﾒｴらみてえのに
関わってるほど➡
But we're so busy we have no time for that these days. So just leave.
今 ｵﾚたちも暇じゃねえんだ｡
消えろや｡
あ～ 幽霊 怖くて
何も手につかねえってか？
Ah, they're scared of ghosts.
かわいそうｱﾙな｡ ﾄｲﾚ一緒に
ついてってあげようか？
Poor babies. Want mommy to stand and guard while you go potty?
武士を愚弄するか～!!
Are you ridiculing a samurai?!
Please come with me to the bathroom.
(近藤)ﾄｲﾚの前まで
お願いしま～す！
I can't believe that you're asking!
(土方)お願いすんのかい！
Well, I was holding off on a trip to the bathroom because I'm scared.
いや さっきから我慢してたんだ｡
でも 怖くてなぁ…｡
(神楽)ほら 行くよ｡
(近藤)はい！
Okay, let's go.
All right.
(土方)おい！
ｱﾝﾀ それでいいのか!?
Hey, are you that scared?
(土方)ｱﾝﾀの人生
それでいいのか おい!!
You wanna seriously live your life like that? Hey!
(土方)はぁ～｡
(土方)ﾃﾒｴら 頼むから このことは
他言しねえでくれ｡
You, please keep quiet about this. I'm begging you.
(土方)頭 下げっから…｡
It looks like you guys really are in trouble. Are you all right?
なんか 相当 大変みたいですね｡
大丈夫なんですか？
(土方)情けねえよ｡
まさか 幽霊騒ぎごときで➡
It's so shameful...
I never thought my army would be so petrified of ghosts like this.
隊が ここまで乱れちまうたぁ…｡
相手に実体があるなら
刀で なんとでもするが➡
If it's something we can see, we can fight it with our swords,
なしときちゃ こっちも
どう出ればいいのか➡
but I have no idea what to do against something we can't see.
皆目 見当もつかねえ…｡
Huh? What? You believe in ghosts?
えっ なに？
おたく 幽霊なんて信じてるの？
ｲﾀﾀﾀﾀ！ 痛いよ～！
Ow! Ow! Help, Mommy! It's the man who injured his head, over here!
お母さ～ん！
ここに 頭 ｹｶﾞした人がいるよ～！
お前 いつか殺してやるからな！
I'll kill you someday.
Don't tell me you saw the woman in the red kimono.
まさか 土方さんも
見たんですかい？ 赤い着物の女｡
わからねえ｡
だが 妙なもんの気配は感じた｡
I can't tell for sure.
But I saw something strange.
(土方)ありゃあ たぶん
人間じゃねえ｡
I don't think it was human.
Ow! Ow! Help! Daddy!
(沖田/銀時)ｲﾃﾃﾃﾃ…！
(２人)痛い 痛いよ お父さ～ん！
ﾊﾞﾝｿｳｺｳ持ってきて～！
Bring me a Band-Aid! The size that can wrap around a whole person!
できるだけ大きな
人 １人 包み込めるくらいの！
(土方)ｵﾒｴら
打ち合わせでもしたのか！
Did you guys rehearse this or something?!
A woman in a red kimono...
赤い着物の女か…｡
たしか そんな怪談ありましたね｡
It reminds me of a ghost story...
ﾎﾞｸが通ってた寺子屋でね➡
At the Temple School I used to go to...that story got passed around a lot.
いっとき そんな怪談が
流行ってたんですよ｡
Let's see... One evening, a student was playing at school.
え～っと なんだっけな…｡
夕暮れどきにね
授業 終わった生徒が➡
寺子屋で遊んでるとね…｡
(近藤)わっ！
Wait for me! I'm begging you... just wait for me.
待っててよ！
頼むから待っててよ!!
こぼすんじゃないよ～｡
Don't make a mess!
もう 誰もいないはずの校舎に…｡
(蚊の羽音)
Nobody was supposed to be in the school building at that time, but...
なんだか 最近 蚊が多いな…｡
So many mosquitoes around...
ｶｯ…!!
...a woman wearing a kimono appeared.
赤い着物を着た女が
いるんだって｡
それで ｢なにしてんだ？｣って
聞くとね…｡
And he asked her what she was doing...
(近藤)ｷﾞｬ～ｯ!!
ｺﾞﾘﾗ～ どうしたか？
ﾁｬｯｸに 皮 はさめたか～？
Gorilla, what's wrong? Got caught in your zipper?
神楽 どうした！
Kagura, what happened?!
He got caught in his zipper.
ﾁｬｯｸに 皮がはさまったｱﾙ！
あ？
Get out of my way!
(土方)どけどけ～!!
(土方)とりゃ！
…なんで そうなるのっ！
How did he end up like that?
♪♪～
うっ… あぁっ…｡
Uh... W-W-Woman in the red kimono...
赤い着物の女が…➡
Uh... Sh-She's coming!
く… 来る！ こっちに来るよ…!!
Kondo-san! Pull yourself together!
(沖田)近藤さん
しっかりしてくだせえ｡
(沖田)いい歳こいて
みっともないですぜ｡ 寝言なんざ｡
Talking in his sleep...and at his age, too.
これは あれだ｡ 昔 泣かした
女の幻覚でも見てんだろ｡
Well, you know... He's probably dreaming of a woman he made cry a long time ago.
近藤さんは 女に泣かされても
泣かしたことはねえ｡
A woman might have made Kondo cry, but he's never made a woman cry.
じゃあ あれだ｡
Then the woman that made you cry has come back to complain some more.
ｵﾒｴが泣かした女が
嫌がらせしにきてんだ｡
I'd never been with a bad woman like that before.
(土方)そんなﾀﾁの悪い女を
相手にした覚えはねえ｡
ふ～ん じゃあ なに？
I see. Then what?
(土方)そんなん知るか！
Heck if I know.
(土方)ただ この屋敷に➡
But I can tell you that there's something strange going on in this building.
得体の知れねえもんがいるのは
確かだ…｡
やっぱり幽霊ですか？
I think that's a ghost.
あ～？ ｵﾚはなぁ 幽霊なんて
非科学的なもんは 信じねえ｡
Ah? I don't believe in unscientific things like ghosts.
ﾑｰ大陸はあると信じてるがな｡
Though I believe in the Lost Continent of Mu.
んっ…？
はぁ～｡
ｱﾎらし｡ つきあいきれねえや｡
That's nonsense. It's too much trouble. Let's go home.
ﾃﾒｴら帰るぞ｡
Gin-san...
銀さん｡
あ？
なんですか？ これ｡
なんだ ｺﾗ｡
What're you doing?
Hey!
ﾃﾒｴらが怖いだろうと思って
気ぃ遣ってやってんだろうが｡
I thought you guys were frightened so I was trying to help you.
Gin-chan, your hands are all sweaty and gross.
銀ちゃんの手 汗ばんでて
気持悪いｱﾙ｡
Ah? What are you talking about?!
あ？ なに言ってやがる！ おい…｡
Ah! The woman in the red kimono!
あっ 赤い着物の女｡
…なにやってんすか？ 銀さん｡
What are you doing, Gin-san?
いや あの ﾑｰ大陸の入り口が…｡
Well, the entrance to Mu...
旦那 ｱﾝﾀもしかして 幽霊が…｡
Say, tough guy... Are you afraid of...a ghost...?
…なんだよ？
What?
Hijikata-san, this guy... Oh?
土方さん ｺｲﾂは… あれ？
♪♪～
土方さん
何をやってるんですかい？
Hijikata-san, what are you doing?
いや あの
ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞ王国の入り口が…｡
Well, the entrance to Mayonnaise Kingdom...
♪♪～
待て待て 待て！ 違う！
Wait, wait, wait! Don't get me wrong!
ｺｲﾂは そうかもしれんが
ｵﾚは違うぞ！
He may be afraid, but not me.
You're the one who's afraid!
ﾋﾞﾋﾞってんのは ｵﾒｴだろ！
ｵﾚは お前 ただ
体内回帰願望があるだけだ！
I just got an urge to return to the womb, is all!
All right, all right. You just go to Mu or Mayonnaise Kingdom or wherever.
わかった わかった｡
ﾑｰ大陸でもﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞ王国でも
どこでも行けよ ｸｿが｡
(２人)なんだ その
さげすんだ目は!!
What does your contemptuous look mean?
なんだ？ おい｡
What's that?
はんっ！ 驚かそうたって ﾑﾀﾞだぜ｡
同じ手は くうかよ｡
Hmph. If you're trying to scare us again, forget it.
The same trick doesn't work twice.
(３人)あっ… ああっ…｡
おい しつけえぞ｡
Hey, come on-you're taking this joke too far.
あぁぁぁ～っ!!
ったく 手の込んだ嫌がらせを…｡
Man, they really put a lot of effort into that put-down.
(土方)これだから ｶﾞｷは…｡
Prankster kids...
You can't deceive us.
(２人)引っかかるかってんだよ｡
ｼｬ～～ｯ!!
(銀時/土方)こ… こんばんは…｡
G-Good evening.
み み み 見ちゃった…！
I-I-I saw her! She was real! She was real!
ﾎﾝﾄにいた！ ﾎﾝﾄにいた!!
(神楽)銀ちゃ～ん!!
Gin-chan!
Forget about them. They're doomed.
(沖田)ﾔﾂらのことは忘れろ！
もうﾀﾞﾒだ！
(物音)
Th...they made it.
き… 切り抜けてきた～！
いや 待て｡ しょってる!?
女しょってるよ おい～!!
...Wait a minute.
They're carrying her! They're carrying the woman!
うわばばばば！ こっち来るな～!!
Get awaaaay!
おい～ なんで逃げんだ お前ら!!
Hey! Why are you running from us?!
Oh? Hold on. Do you feel something heavy on your back?
あれ？ ちょっと待て｡
おい なんか 後ろ重くねえか？
I don't know! I have no idea!
(土方)知らん！ ｵﾚは知らん！
I'm sure someone is on us; I feel something heavy.
いや 乗ってるって｡
だって 重いもん これ｡
(土方)うるせえな
自分で確認すればいいだろうが！
Shut up. Why don't you check then?
Can't you just take a look at it?!
お前 ちょっとくらい見てくれても
いいんじゃねえの～？
ちょっと待て… こうしよう｡
せ～の で ２人同時に振り向く｡
Hold on. Let's do this.
Let's both turn around and look at the same time.
お前 絶対 見ろよ！
裏切るなよ！ 絶対 見ろよ!!
Just make sure you do it! Don't cheat me!
You definitely look back!
Here we go!
(銀時/土方)せ～の！
(銀時/土方)こ… こんばんは…｡
G-Good evening.
(銀時と土方の叫び声)
やられた… 今度こそ やられた…｡
They died! They really died!
しめたぜ｡ これで 副長の座は➡
Yes! I'll finally be promoted to Vice-chief.
ｵﾚのもんだい｡
言ってる場合か！
Whatever!
(沖田)おい 誰か
明かり持ってねえかい？
Hey, does anybody have a light? Oh, there's a mosquito coil.
(沖田)おっ 蚊取り線香があった｡
なんだよ あれ…
なんで あんなん いんだよ～｡
What's that? What the hell is that?
新八～ 銀ちゃん
死んじゃったｱﾙか？
Shinpachi, did Gin-chan die? Did he?
ねぇ 死んじゃったｱﾙか？
実は 前に 土方さんを
亡き者にするため➡
Well, I once tried to summon an evil spirit so Hijikata-san would die.
外法で 妖魔を
呼び出したことがあったんでぃ｡
Maybe it's left over from back then...
ありゃ もしかしたら
そんときの…｡
How black is your soul, anyway?!
ｱﾝﾀ どんだけ
腹ん中 真っ黒なんですか！
Are you the root of this evil? You bastard-I'll avenge Gin!
(神楽)元凶は お前ｱﾙか！
おのれ 銀ちゃんの仇～!!
Hey, hey! Stop it! This place is too small for that!
あぁ もう！
狭いのに やめろっつうの！
Every time you see each other, why are you...
なんで お前ら
会うと いっつも…｡
(争う声)
ｷｬ～～～ｯ!!
出… 出すぺらぁど～～!!
I-It's here! Sorry.
す す… すみません！
とりあえず すんません！
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry!
ﾏｼﾞ すんません!!
ﾃﾒｴらも謝れ ﾊﾞｶ野郎！
You guys apologize, too!
If you apologize from your heart by bowing your head, it will reach everyone, stupid!
人間 心から 頭 下げれば➡
どんなﾔﾂにも 心 通じんだよ
ﾊﾞｶ野郎！
Seriously! We'll even lick the soles of your shoes, so please forgive us.
あの ﾎﾝﾄ 靴の裏も なめますんで
勘弁してよ ﾏｼﾞで！
I don't taste very good... I don't taste very good... I don't taste...
ﾎﾞｸなんか食べても
おいしくないよ…｡
ﾎﾞｸなんか食べても… ん？
あれ… いない｡
Oh! She's gone.
な… なんで？
Wh-Why?
(蚊の羽音)
(２人)うるせえって
言ってんだよ ﾌﾟﾝﾌﾟﾝよ!!
Stop with the annoying sound effects!
ﾃﾒｴ 生きてやがったのか｡
...You survived.
(土方)お前こそ
悪運の強い野郎だ｡
You must have the luck of the devil!
あ… あれは どこ行った？
Wh-Where did the thing go?
知らん｡ 他の連中のほうに
向かったんだろ｡
Dunno. After the others probably.
逃げやがったのか…｡
It ran away...
実はよ… さっき
追いかけられてるとき➡
You know what?
While I was being chased by it, I was giving it my "Badass" look.
ず～っと ｱｲﾂに
ﾒﾝﾁきってたんだ～｡
あれ 効いたな｡
I guess it worked.
(土方)ほざけよ ﾃﾒｴ｡
Whatever. While I was being chased by it, I kept pinching that thing.
ｵﾚなんて 追いかけられてるとき
ず～っと ﾔﾂを つねってた｡
ちっせえんだよ｡
ｵﾚなんて お前…｡
(物音)
You're so small-minded...
(ｶｴﾙの鳴き声)
さ～て 水も浴びて
すっきりしたし➡
Well, I had a nice swim and am all refreshed. It's time for a counterattack.
そろそろ反撃といくかな｡
Don't try to act tough.
Your voice is quivering.
ﾑﾘすんなよ｡ 声が震えてるぜ｡
ﾔﾂは ｵﾚが しとめる｡
ﾍﾀﾚは 家で 屁たれてろ｡
I'll take care of that thing. You go lay down, princess
ﾋﾞﾋﾞってんのは ﾃﾒｴだろ｡
わざわざ 池に隠れたのは➡
I think you're the one who's frightened.
I know you hid in the pond because you already wet your pants, huh?!
股間が
ﾋﾞｯｼｮﾘだったからじゃねえの？
What?! I'll exorcise you before I get that ghost!
(土方)なんだ ﾃﾒｴ｡ 幽霊の前に
ﾃﾒｴを退治してやろうか？
ﾃﾒｴには いろいろと
借りがあるからな｡
(蚊の羽音)
I owe you a lot, so I'll pay you back with interest!
延滞料金も含めて きっちり
返してやってもいいんだぜ！
あ？ 何か貸したっけ？
(羽音)
Huh? Did I lend you something? Don't worry, you can keep it!
もういいよ あげるよ｡
(羽音)
I already bought a new NES game.
ﾎﾞｸ もう 新しいﾌｧﾐｺﾝ買ったから｡
(羽音)
Shut up, already!!
(２人)なんだ うるせえな!!
♪♪～
ｼｬ～～！
あああああ がぁ…!!
(２人)あ…！
やっぱり 思ったとおりだ｡
Just as I expected.
この人も… この人も この人も｡
This man...
and this man, as well as this one...
幽霊にやられた人は みんな一様に
蚊に刺されたような傷がある｡
All these men, who were hit by ghosts, have huge mosquito bites...
That is...
あれは… 幽霊なんかじゃない｡
not a ghost.
がぁっ!!
(土方/銀時)うわっ！
うっ！ おおお おい…
あんなん ありか？
H-H-Hey! What the heck was that?!
(土方)ととと…
飛んでんじゃねえか！
It's f-f-flying!
H-H-Hey, are you scared?
ななな なに おお お前…
ひょっとして ﾋﾞﾋﾞﾋﾞ… ﾋﾞﾋﾞってんの？
ﾊﾞﾊﾞﾊﾞ ﾊﾞｶ言うな！
N-N-No way! Who do you think I am?
ｵｵｵ… ｵﾚを
誰だと思ってんだ ﾃﾒｴ！
じょ 上等じゃねえか｡
I'm not scared!
よ よ～し じゃ お前は
ﾔﾂを引きつけろ｡
All right. You be the bait.
Then I'll...do that...
ｵﾚは あの～… あれするから｡
おい！
あれするから って なんだ!?
Hey! What does "that" mean? Escape? Are you going to skip out?
ｴｽｹｰﾌﾟか!?
ずらかるつもりだろ ﾃﾒｴ!!
違うって｡ あの… あれだ
ﾊﾞｽﾞｰｶで撃つ！
N-No way. Um...I'm going to shoot it with a bazooka.
(土方)ﾊﾞｽﾞｰｶなんて
どこに あんだよ？
Where's the bazooka?
Everyone has a bazooka in their heart.
人は皆 心に ﾊﾞｽﾞｰｶもってんだよ！
You just can't escape.
ﾃﾒｴだけ逃げようったって
そうはいかねえ！
おい なにしてんだ ﾃﾒｴ！
Hey, what are you doing?!
がぁ～～！
うぉっ！
ひっ！
敵前逃亡は 士道不覚悟だ｡
Running from an enemy goes against Bushido principles.
もっぺん 侍道を やり直すんだな｡
You had better study the code from scratch.
ずぅおっ!!
What the hell are you doing?!
なにしやがんだ ﾃﾒｴ!!
(土方)がっ!!
ｹｯ｡ ｵﾚに 侍道を説くなんざ
100年 早いんだよ｡ …ん？
You'll need another hundred years to tell me about the way of the samurai.
あれ？
Oh?
あの～ どうもすみませんでした｡
Well, I'm sorry for what I did.
(天人)私 地球でいう
いわゆる 蚊みたいな天人で➡
I'm an Amanto. I'm like an earth mosquito.
最近 会社の上司との間に
子供ができちゃって➡
I got pregnant with my boss at work.
この子 産むために
ｴﾈﾙｷﾞｰが必要だったんです｡
And I needed energy for the delivery.
(天人)あの人には家庭があるから
私１人で この子 育てようって…｡
He has a family, so I decided to raise my baby myself.
I was looking for blood and found the perfect place full of hot-blooded men, so...
それで 血を求めて
さまよってたら➡
男だらけで ﾑﾝﾑﾝしてる
絶好のｴｻ場を見つけて つい…｡
I'm really sorry.
ﾎﾝﾄ すみませんでした｡
But I wanted to be strong. I wanted to be strong enough to raise my baby!
でも 私 強くなりたかったの｡
この子 育てるために
強くなりたかったの！ がぁっ!!
Sorry, but can you stop making that horrible face?
(近藤)すみません
その 顔の影 強くするの➡
やめてくれませんか｡
ったくよぉ
幽霊にしろ 蚊にしろ➡
...Anyway, it doesn't matter whether it's a ghost or a mosquito.
はた迷惑だってのに
かわりはねえな｡
It's another pain in the butt to everyone.
(土方)はた迷惑なのは ﾃﾒｴだ｡
You're a pain in the butt!
I'm not going to give you any reward. Just leave.
報酬なんぞ やらんと
言ってるだろ｡ 消えろ｡
But don't forget that it was my final blow that solved everything.
ｵﾒｴ ｵﾚの一撃が すべてを
解決したことを 忘れたか？
なに言ってんだ｡
What are you talking about?
ﾃﾒｴの前に ｵﾚの一撃で
すべて決着ついてたんだよ｡
I made a blow before you, and that solved everything.
(土方)ﾃﾒｴなんざ いなくても
ｵﾚだけで どうにかなったんだ｡
I handled it without your help.
ﾋﾞﾋﾞりまくってたくせに
よく言うぜ｡
Yeah, you sure talk big-but you were shaking in your boots.
まさか 鬼の副長と恐れられる男が
お化けを恐れてるとは➡
Who would believe the terrifying Vice-chief is scared of ghosts?
お天道様でも思うめえ｡
あれは ｵﾒｴ
ﾋﾞﾋﾞってたんじゃねえ➡
You know, I was not scared. I was just startled.
ﾋﾞｯｸﾘしてただけだ｡
大きな間違いだぞ これは｡
It's a huge difference.
(土方)お前は
明らかに ﾋﾞﾋﾞってたけどな｡
I bet you were really scared.
ありゃ お前
企画に のってやっただけだ｡
You know, I was pretending that I was following the scripts.
むしろ ｵﾚは こういうの好きだぜ｡
これから 毎回やろうか｡
Actually, I prefer doing it like this. Let's do it every week...
Gin-chan, it's time to go...
銀ちゃん そろそろ帰… ん？
何やってるｱﾙか？ ２人とも｡
What are you two doing?
Well, I dropped my contact...
(土方/銀時)いや
ｺﾝﾀｸﾄ落としちゃって…｡
[Preview]
It's hot! Hot!
Why do I have to get sweaty working to buy a fan?!
I'm here to get something to cool down, but I'm getting hotter!
The next episode is: "If You Go to Sleep with the Fan On You'll Get a Stomachache, So Be Careful."
[Also, the Odd Jobs go fishing. "If You're a Man, Try the Swordfish!"]
[But what they caught was a Kappa, the master of the lake? Ebina-san? What the... He actually has a name?!]
Finally, I've got enough mayonnaise!
♬『ゼッコーチョー！』
♬～